

MD. TANVIR AHMED

### **CONTACT**

- **+**880-1753781569
- ★ tanvirpoly@gmail.com
- tanvirpx.rf.gd
- Mirpur, Shewrapara



#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

JQuery

PHP(Laravel)

PHP(CodeIgniter)

Python(Django)

Java

Android Studio

Programming C

AutoCAD

Photoshop

Illustrator

Video Editing

SEO

ChatGPT

### **LANGUAGE**



#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a Computer Science & Engineering(CSE) graduate focused on dedicating my skills and knowledge to solving problems in the real world. My work ranges from Research (Image Processing, Machine learning, Computer Vision), Web Developer (PHP-Laravel, PHP-Codelgniter, Python, Django, MySQL), and Graphics Design (Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator).



#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

> Sunshine IT (Full Time)

Designation: Software Support Engineer(POS, Inventory)
Duration: March, 2024 to Present

> MyJobs (Full Time)

Designation: Jr. IT Executive & Business Development

Duration: March, 2023 to October, 2023

Project(01): https://github.com/tanvirpoly/Job Potal

Live: https://www.myjobs.com.bd

Project(02): https://github.com/tanvirpoly/Poster-Maker

Others Work: https://shorturl.at/nxzF0

> Perfect Air Conditioning and Refrigeration Pty Ltd

Designation: IT Executive, Australia(Remote)

Duration: August, 2021 to Present

Project(01): https://perfectrepair.com.au/ Project(02): https://comfortair.com.au/



#### **INTERNSHIP**

> DIGI5 LTD(Remote)

Designation: Laravel Backend Developer(Internship)

Duration: August, 2023 to February, 2024 Test Project: https://shorturl.at/iuDUW Project(01): https://shorturl.at/ANXY3

Live: https://swasavar.org/

Project(02): https://shorturl.at/eBCV8

Live: https://app7.digi5.net/login

> Intern at Green University Language Center

Duration: 6 months



#### **AWARDS/ ACHIEVEMENTS**

- CSE Carnival (2020), ICT Quiz Competition (3rd place),
   Green University Computer Club
- Academic Excellence VC's Awards (2019), Green University of Bangladesh
- Reading Program (2019), Successfully Completing the Book Reading Program, BRITISH COUNCIL



#### **UNIVERSITY (PUBLICATION)**

> Tanvir, et al. "An Image-based Digital Forensic Investigation Framework for Crime Analysis." 2023 International Conference on Next-Generation Computing, IoT and Machine Learning (NCIM). IEEE, 2023.

Published in: 2023 International Conference on Next-Generation Computing, IoT and Machine Learning (NCIM); Date of Conference: 16-17 June 2023; Date Added to IEEE Xplore: 21 August 2023;

**DOI:** 10.1109/NCIM59001.2023.10212439

Paper: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10212439

Github: https://github.com/tanvirpoly/Image-Based-Digital-Foren-

sic-Investigation-Framework



#### PROFESSIONAL TRANNING

> Professional Web Application Development (PWAD): Islamic Development

Bank-Bangladesh Islamic Solidarity

Wakf (IsDB-BISEW) IT Scholarship Project

Tranning Center: US Software Ltd.

Authority: IsDB-BISEW Duration: 460 hrs

Project(01): https://github.com/tanvirpoly/My-Personal-Portfolio-Website

Project(02): https://github.com/tanvirpoly/Online-Registration-Form

Project(03): github.com/tanvirpoly/Online-Restaurant-Management-System

> Professional Graphics Design Learning & Earning Development Project(LEDP)

Tranning Center: Soft Park Ltd.

Authority: ICT Devision Duration: 200 hrs

Certificate: https://ledp.ictd.gov.bd/certificate/?regid=222258

#### **EDUCATION**

> Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Completed in: 2022

and Engineering CGPA: 3.52

Green University of Bangladesh

> Diploma in Engineering in Electronics Completed in: 2017

**Technology** CGPA: 3.46

Comilla Polytechnic Institute, Comilla

Secondary School Certificate Completed in: 2012

Government Laboratory High School GPA: 4.13

## **PERSONAL IDENTITY**

> Date of Birth: 15 Dec 1997 > Passport: A01389253

> NID: 2403281807

# REFERENCES

- > PROF. DR. MD. SAIFUL AZAD
- > Professor and Dean, FSE
- > Cell: 01747230418
- > Email: dean@fse.green.edu.bd > jahid@cse.green.edu.bd
- > MR. MD. JAHIDUL ISLAM
- > Assistant Professor
- > Cell: 01790-100915
- > Engr. Muhammad Ferdaus
- > Deputy-Chief Engineer (Electrical)
- > Green University of Bangladesh > Green University of Bangladesh > National Tubes Limited, An Enterprise of BSEC under the Ministry of Industries
  - > ferdaus.doel@gmail.com